Life's too short to be a background character.
Free Guy is a comedy, adventure, science fiction film directed by Shawn Levy.
A bank teller discovers he is actually a background player in an open-world
video game, and decides to become the hero of his own story.
Now, in a world where there are no limits, he is determined to be the
guy who saves his world his way before it's too late.
Guy, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Millie Rusk / Molotovgirl, played by Jodie Comer.
Buddy, played by Lil Rel Howery.
Keys, played by Joe Keery.
Mouser, played by Utkarsh Ambudkar.
Antwan, played by Taika Waititi.
Free Guy is a 2021 American science fiction action-comedy film directed and produced by Shawn
Levy from a screenplay by Matt Lieberman and Zak Penn, and a story by Lieberman.
The film stars Ryan Reynolds as a bank teller who discovers that he is a non-player character in a massively multiplayer online game,
who then partners with a player to find evidence that a gaming company's CEO stole the source code of the player's game.
The cast also features Jodie Comer, Lil Rel Howery,
Utkarsh Ambudkar, Joe Keery, and Taika Waititi.
Lieberman began writing the script in 2016, which was
acquired by 20th Century Fox shortly after.
Levy passed on the script but reconsidered after Hugh Jackman introduced him to Reynolds, resulting in
him leaving the film adaptation of the Uncharted video game he had been developing.
The acquisition of 21st Century Fox by Disney made Free Guy one of the first films
produced by the studio to continue production under Disney's ownership.
Filming took place in Massachusetts and California between May and July 2019.
After Free Guy was delayed two times by the COVID-19 pandemic, it premiered at the 74th Locarno Film Festival on August
10, 2021, and was released theatrically in the United States by 20th Century Studios three days later.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $331.5 million worldwide against a $100–125 million production budget, and received generally positive reviews
from critics, who compared it to films and video games such as Ready Player One, The Truman Show, The Matrix, Grand Theft Auto, and Fortnite.
It received a nomination for Best Visual Effects at the 94th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of hero, artificial intelligence
(a.i.), video game, virtual reality, gun.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.